# Michael Peter Nair

Melbourne, Victoria, Australia • <u>michael.p.nair@gmail.com</u> +61416436987 • <u>linkedin.com/in/michael-nair/</u>

## **Profile: Fullstack Software Engineer**

I am a Web Developer with a previous background in Financial Analysis who is keen to use my skills and experience in programming, data analytics and working with teams to come together to create solutions. I completed General Assembly's Software Engineering Immersive, where I have learned to work confidently with both frontend and backend technologies through creating apps with React front end, third-party API integrations and databases.

### **Relevant Experience**

APSEC Funds Management 2021 to 2023

## **Quantitative Analyst**

- Research, develop and test pairs trading algorithms for Australian stocks and also for US stocks.
- Create reports for use in client facing newsletters.
- Get data from databases and calculate fields for reports for third party stakeholders.
- Ensure that the managed funds are priced accurately and assets are accounted for accurately.

Lincoln Indicators 2016 to 2021

#### **Fund Administrator**

- Took additional project to develop models for portfolio construction of US equities from analysis of fundamental factors.
- Took additional project for Financial Modelling to calculate asset risk and asset covariance.
- Took additional project to perform backtesting of Technical indicators on Australian equities with prior fundamental screening.
- Perform ongoing analysis on managed fund products, Australian equities and US equities
- Ensure that the managed funds are priced accurately and assets are accounted for accurately.
- Liaise with brokers to perform trades.

Fastman 2013 to 2015

#### **Business Support**

- Developing efficient reporting processes as the company transitions from MYOB to Xero accounting systems.
- Creating easily repeatable reporting on Key Performance Indicators (KPI).
- Programming CRM to implement a more streamlined work process and to generate more accurate and timely reports.

#### Education

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly, 2023

Completed Level 1 Charted Financial Analyst (CFA) Exam | CFA Institute, 2012

Bachelor of Commerce (Degree with Honours) Major in Actuarial Studies | University of Melbourne, 2007 - 2010

## **Technical Proficiencies**

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript,, Python, SQL, R, Matlab
- Technologies: React, Express, Node, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Skills: Full Stack Development, Financial Analysis, Data Analysis
- Other Skills: Funds Management, Financial Modelling, Developing Trading Algorithms, Xero